JULES O'DEA

juleso.now.sh jules.odea@gmail.com 021 195 3885

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a highly creative individual with several years experience as a frontend developer after many years in the hospitality industry. I initially enrolled full-time at the Yoobee School of Design and graduated with top grades after successfully completing a Diploma in Web and UX Design.

This knowledge led me to being immediately valuable in my role contributing to the companies progressive web app repository using Ionic and Typescript as well as website redesign implementation.

EXPERIENCE

Jitbug

MARCH 2020 - PRESENT

Frontend Developer Digital Designer

Yoobee School of Design

JULY 2018 - JULY 2019

Diploma Web & UX design Tasks at Jitbug involved redesign of company website. Including wireframing, user interface design and creating the static site with Jekyll. Working on and making contributions to Jitbug PWA repository for a teaching recruitment app working with Ionic and Typescript.

Successfully completed a Diploma in Web and UX Design from the Yoobee School of Design with top marks. The diploma course provided me with a solid understanding of web foundations, HTML5 / CSS3, Javascript and Adobe XD to collaborate and create dynamic compelling user experiences. My projects were delivered using the agile methodology, this experience prepared me to be immediately valuable in my new role as a frontend developer.

PROJECTS

eCommerce Store

https://jponz-live.herokuapp.com

Online store using React and Redux Store to implement a online shop. Firebase and authentication integration. Stripe API to handle the basic payment system.

Black Estate Redesign

https://julesodea.github.io/be/

Redesign of a current website for Black Estate winery in Canterbury, The project was created in React.

News API

https://thebulletin.netlify.app

Throught the use of Google News API I was able to bring up to date news articles to the user. The site shows the top 10 news articles currently from BBC news

Note App

https://noted.netlify.app

Users can add items to their list, edit any items they have added and also delete items. A minimalistic design was used to make the user experience friendly.

EDUCATION

Yoobee School of Design

JULY 2018 - JULY 2019

Diploma
Web & UX design

Successfully completed a Diploma in Web and UX Design from the Yoobee School of Design with top marks. The diploma course provided me with a solid understanding of web foundations and user experience design.

AUT University

JULY 2010 - JULY 2014

Majoring in Management Bachelor of Business Completed a Bachelor of Business at AUT majoring in Management. Gained an understanding of professional senior management and how modern businesses remain competitive.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Javascript	HTML 5	Management
React	CSS 3	eBusiness
Ionic	Redux	Figma
Typescript	Git	Sketch

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Chef

FEBRUARY 2018 - JULY 2018

Orphans Kitchen

Duties include day to day running of a very busy kitchen for morning service. Which involves ordering, menu planing. Provided leadership and training to new staff memebrs and communication with suppliers.

Head Chef

FEBRUARY 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Atomic Coffee

Duties include working in a small and very busy kitchen at the Atomic Coffee cafe headquarters. Undertook menu changes for seasonal menu and ordering of all product for day to day service. Provided leadership to new staff. Direct communication with various suppliers.

Assistant Production Manager

IAN 2013 - 2015

Coffee Lab

Duties include roasting, supply chain management of coffee from raw product to end product. Customer relationship management, training of new staff and key holder for opening and closing of business. Management of online store and stock. Customer service and sales

REFERENCES

References avalaible on request.